CURRICULUM VITAE

Tarun Bisht

Email: itstarunbisht@gmail.com
Website: https://tarunbisht.com
Location: Uttarakhand, India

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is to contribute to the advancements of Al. My research interest includes Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Speech Recognition, Generative Al, Self-Supervised learning in vision and speech understanding, which includes learning feature representations for images in a self-supervised manner, creating few shots classifiers and object detection systems, streaming end to end speech recognition system etc.

EDUCATION

M. Sc. in Computer Science, Kumaun University (2018 - 2020)

- Thesis: Application of object detection in home surveillance system
- Research Focus: Creating low compute object detection systems for home surveillance, majorly deals
 with the problem of monkey theft detection in our area.
- Percentage: 76.55%, Division: First, Rank: 1st

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Physics and Mathematics, Kumaun University (2015 – 2018)

Percentage: 65.48%, Division: First

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

The Sound Of AI - Open Source Research, (2020 - Ongoing)

The group aims to create a piece of collaborative research in the field of AI music. I am currently working as a research co-coordinator for speech to text division. Our responsibility includes the conversion of speech into text and its integration in the production environment.

Research Project - Kumaun University, (2020)

I have done my master's thesis on the application of object detection in home surveillance, which mainly deals with the problem of creating cheap alert systems for monkey theft detection in our area and alert the user when detected.

National Children Science Congress (NCSC), (2010-2012)

Actively presented research experience papers in NCSC. The research topics include Land resources: use for prosperity, save for posterity and Energy: explore, harness and conserve.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Worked as a private tutor alongside college, the teaching subjects include Computer Science for bachelor's students and Physics, Mathematics for 10 to 12th-grade students. I also write educational tutorials related to computer science and artificial intelligence on my <u>website</u>.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web and Application Development

- Created solutions for my university, related to employee and library management.
- Developing and integrating machine-learning applications.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- GATE (2021): Organized by IIT Bombay (Qualified)
- UGC NET (2020): Organized by UGC (University Grants Commission) for Assistant Professor (Qualified)
- Rank 2 in object detection competition organized by dockship.io